<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blair MacIntyre</title>
    <description>Professor, Designer, Husband, Father
</description>
    <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://blairmacintyre.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 11:00:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 11:00:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To Mozilla!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to start a new job, while on leave from Georgia Tech, as a Principal Research Scientist at Mozilla&lt;label for=&quot;moz&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;moz&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/mozilla.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blair MacIntyre&lt;br /&gt;Principal Research Scientist&lt;/span&gt;. I’ll be working for Sean White in the Emerging Technologies Group, looking at adding AR capabilities to the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;For those&lt;/span&gt;  of you know know me, or follow my work, this is a natural progression for me.  I’ve been leading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://argon.gatech.edu&quot;&gt;Argon&lt;/a&gt; project at Georgia Tech since 2009, looking at what it issues related to using the Web as an infrastructure for AR. We have just released the the 4th version of the Argon browser (Argon4 for iOS) and open-sourced the AR web framework &lt;em&gt;argon.js&lt;/em&gt;, all of which can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://argonjs.io&quot;&gt;argonjs.io&lt;/a&gt;.  This version is reasonable solid, mature and usable, and the GT team is actively working on enhancing it and finally porting it to new platforms (like Android).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;So the next&lt;/span&gt;  logical step for me is to see if we can take AR into a “real” browser ecosystem. I am really excited to join Mozilla. Aside from having an opportunity to work with great people and advancing ideas I’ve devoted myself to for the past 7 or 8 years, I am passionate about contributing to the open internet and being part of an organization dedicated to the cause. I don’t know all the things I will get up to over the next little while, but I wouldn’t be surprised to find myself getting involved in a lot of aspects of what is happening there, both technical (AR, WebVR, browser architectures, etc.) and non-technical (educational, advocacy, policy, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my motivations for getting my blog “functional” again is so that I can blog about the journey and what I am up to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/07/welcome-to-mozilla/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/07/welcome-to-mozilla/</guid>
        
        <category>mozilla</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Augmented Reality artist Pablo Valbuena</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, I’ve finished cleaning up the blog on my personal website, which I started moving from Wordpress to Jekyll earlier this year.  As I was going through the posts, I ran across a lot of old content I want to revisit, but was especially pleased to see an &lt;a href=&quot;/2008/09/30/ar-art-todaysart08/&quot;&gt;old post&lt;/a&gt; from back in 2008 about the &lt;em&gt;architectural projective AR&lt;/em&gt; art of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/&quot;&gt;Pablo Valbuena&lt;/a&gt;.  He’s continued making really interesting pieces, here are a few of the newer ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kinematope&lt;label for=&quot;kinematope&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;kinematope&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/kinematope/&quot;&gt;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/kinematope/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/113798262&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kinematope&lt;label for=&quot;timetilings&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;timetilings&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/time-tiling-stuk/&quot;&gt;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/time-tiling-stuk/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/70587267&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, here’s a link back to the first one I saw, the projective outdoor art project at The Hague, called &lt;em&gt;N 520437 E 041900 [the hague city hall]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;hague&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;hague&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/n-520437-e-041900/&quot;&gt;http://www.pablovalbuena.com/selectedwork/n-520437-e-041900/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/20162149&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/06/ar-art-pablo-valbuena/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/06/ar-art-pablo-valbuena/</guid>
        
        <category>architectural art</category>
        
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AR presentation with argon.js + aframe.js + reveal.js</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a talk (with my colleage Maribeth) at Moxie’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://moxieusa.com/futurexlive&quot;&gt;FutureXLive&lt;/a&gt; event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk was about &lt;em&gt;Democratizing AR&lt;/em&gt;, the process of making AR accessible to many more people as a medium of for creating and sharing experiences, applications, and ideas. The main point of the presentation was that integrating AR technologies with the Web is the way to do this: democratization is not just about having “easy, simple tools” for creating content, but also having control over how and when the content is made available.  The requirment to build, polish, port, ship and maintain apps puts technologies like AR out of the hands of many people, in contrast to the simplicity of putting ideas on a web site.  Consider how much easier it was for me to write this blog post that ship an app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To drive the point home, I created and delivered the presentation using web technologies. I started with &lt;a href=&quot;http://lab.hakim.se/reveal-js/#/&quot;&gt;reveal.js&lt;/a&gt;, a web presentation framework I’ve used in the past, and then added in our AR web framework &lt;a href=&quot;http://argonjs.io&quot;&gt;argon.js&lt;/a&gt; to AR-enable the presentation, and Mozilla’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://aframe.io/&quot;&gt;A-Frame&lt;/a&gt; to simplify the creation of 3D content. (I’d already modified &lt;em&gt;A-Frame&lt;/em&gt; to integrate with &lt;em&gt;argon.js&lt;/em&gt;, creating an &lt;a href=&quot;http://argonjs.io/argon-aframe&quot;&gt;argon-aframe.js&lt;/a&gt; that I also included). I needed to create a modified presentation style (that included transparent backgrounds, and a few other tweaks) for &lt;em&gt;reveal.js&lt;/em&gt;, but aside from that things mostly just “worked.”   The bulk of the work was figuring what I wanted to show, when to use AR and when to use 2D, and so on.  The source for the presentation is on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/blairmacintyre/futurexlive&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, it’s messy and undocumented, but pretty “straightforward” if you understand these libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the presentation with our AR-capable web browser &lt;a href=&quot;http://argon.gatech.edu&quot;&gt;Argon4&lt;/a&gt;, you can try it by downloading Argon4 for iOS and pointing it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://blairmacintyre.me/futurexlive&quot;&gt;http://blairmacintyre.me/futurexlive&lt;/a&gt;. Since it uses web technology, I can include it here, inside and iframe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;http://blairmacintyre.me/futurexlive&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;The presentation&lt;/span&gt;  probably doesn’t make as much sense as it could without my narrative to go along with it, as you’d expect&lt;label for=&quot;moxievideo&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;moxievideo&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Hopefully the video of my presentation will be made available; I’ll post it to the blog when/if it is, or create a new video just to show this in action. &lt;/span&gt;. And, of course, since (&lt;em&gt;whatever browser you are using&lt;/em&gt;) doesn’t support AR technology, the “AR” slides are likely showing up as plain white slides without AR content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On slide 4, I use political activism an example of something that may be hard to publish through apps stores (and may be blocked), and also as an example of something that is small-and-trivial-to-make and hard to justify the expense of creating and maintaining apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On slides 9-11, there are some live AR examples.  They were tweaked to work well during the presentation, such that the content was easily visible while I talked.  So the collection of spinning cubes on slide 9 covered the visible parts of the room from the viewpoint of the stage.  (If your browser support geolocation, you should see some of these on slide 9, over a white background, even if it doesn’t support orientation, since the default orientation is &lt;em&gt;North&lt;/em&gt; and part of the room faced north.) This is a standard trick of presenting AR live:  you need to take the space into account!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slide 12 illustrates how simple adding &lt;em&gt;A-Frame&lt;/em&gt; AR content to the presentation was. You should move &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; on this slide (swipe on a touch screen, or use the down arrow key) to see the code snippets for all the examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slide 15 was something I only wanted to dive into more detail on if I had time (I did, it turned out). So again, slide &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; to see some slides about using &lt;a href=&quot;http://twinery.com&quot;&gt;twine&lt;/a&gt; to create 3D AR stories.  A slide showing the &lt;em&gt;twine&lt;/em&gt; storyboard for an interactive AR book I was creating, some &lt;em&gt;twine source code&lt;/em&gt; for the back cover of the book showing a mix of 2D and 3D content creation.  I’m not asserting here that &lt;em&gt;twine&lt;/em&gt; is the ideal AR authoring tool, but rather that by bring AR to the web, we can support integrating AR as a content element in existing web content tools, bringing AR to folks where they live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you’ll see on Slide 17 that I have a new email address!  More on that in a later blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/06/argon-aframe-reveal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/06/argon-aframe-reveal/</guid>
        
        <category>argon</category>
        
        <category>aframe</category>
        
        <category>presentation</category>
        
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>argon</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finally Finished Moving My Site to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I decided to move my personal website and blog out of Wordpress on onto Jekyll.  There were many reasons for this;  partly I was tired of dealine with Wordpress (yet again, and update to Wordpress and the plugins I was using caused me to have to spend time just getting things working again), but mostly I wanted more control over the blog so that I could start integrating more interesting content into it (this still hasn’t happened, but it’s “in progress”).    I’m planning to add some AR content to the site, soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I finally finished one thing, though:  my old blog posts are all “cleaned up” and functional again.  All the comments were moved from Wordpress over the Disqus and remain attached to the correct posts, I’ve fixed the content so videos and images show up again, and even updated the layout of some posts to use the new layout I’m using, &lt;a href=&quot;http://clayh53.github.io/tufte-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Tufte-Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, along with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/inukshuk/jekyll-scholar&quot;&gt;Jekyll-Scholar&lt;/a&gt; plugin that makes it easy to academic references and content to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably isn’t too exciting for most people, but I’m happy it’s finally done, and really happy with using Jekyll moving forward.  Right now the site is hosted on GitHub, but that may change if GitHub doesn’t improve their support for HTTPS on sites with custom domains. Now that &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org&quot;&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; makes it super-simple to get valid HTTPS certificates, and my hosting provider &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dreamhost.com/&quot;&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt; supports that service, I may move my site back there (but will still keep the source code on GitHub, obviously).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/05/site-fixed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/11/05/site-fixed/</guid>
        
        <category>blog, technology</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Animated Interfaces Gaining Traction</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a fan of animated interfaces for years, going back to the amazing work that Sun’s &lt;em&gt;Self&lt;/em&gt; team did on the &lt;em&gt;Self&lt;/em&gt; user interface.  The &lt;em&gt;Morphic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;maloney-smith&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;maloney-smith&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Maloney:1995:DLM:215585.215636&quot;&gt;Maloney, J. H., &amp;amp; Smith, R. B. (1995). Directness and Liveness in the Morphic User Interface Construction Environment. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface and Software Technology&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 21–28). New York, NY, USA: ACM. doi:10.1145/215585.215636&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;user interface used in &lt;em&gt;Self&lt;/em&gt; was interesting in a lot of ways, especially how it bent over backwards to make the interface feel alive and like you were truly directly manipulating the objects you were creating and working with, both as you programmed and as you used it. I particularly like how the team adapted traditional animation techniques for the UI, building off the years of experience traditional animators had in making cartoon animations feel “real”&lt;label for=&quot;chang-ungar&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;chang-ungar&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Chang:1993:ACU:168642.168647&quot;&gt;Chang, B.-W., &amp;amp; Ungar, D. (1993). Animation: From Cartoons to the User Interface. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the 6th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 45–55). New York, NY, USA: ACM. doi:10.1145/168642.168647&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been reminded recently of the various ways &lt;em&gt;Self&lt;/em&gt; leveraged traditional animation to make the UI feel more solid and alive when I read articles about some of the new trends in adding motion to interfaces. Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/design/spec/material-design/&quot;&gt;Material Design&lt;/a&gt; emphasizes motion, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thekineticui.com/so-what-is-motion-design/&quot;&gt;Motion Design&lt;/a&gt; has been invading traditional 2D UI’s. A few days ago I read Craig Dehner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.prototypr.io/your-app-login-is-boring-bring-it-to-life-with-motion-7ac2547d9c5f#.meydnr8pq&quot;&gt;Your App Login is Boring, Bring it to Life with Motion&lt;/a&gt; article (if you haven’t read the article, or browsed his site, I encourage you to)&lt;label for=&quot;app-login&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;app-login&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/app-login-boring.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An example of what Craig talks about in his article&lt;/span&gt;.  I think Craig’s points are really good, and his focus on &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the animation is trying to convey that reinforces what’s happening in the interface.  Reading the two papers above and comparing them to Craig’s post is worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animation is not gloss or polish: used right it can make your interfaces easier to understand, clearer and more fun to use.  The &lt;em&gt;Self&lt;/em&gt; team demonstrated this 20 years ago, and it’s nice to see modern UI designers continuing this work!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/03/23/animated-interfaces-gaining-traction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2016/03/23/animated-interfaces-gaining-traction/</guid>
        
        <category>adaptive</category>
        
        <category>animation</category>
        
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>commercial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing for UIST 2014 &amp;#8230; decade-old technology rises from the dead!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;uist-dart&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;uist-dart&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2014/09/2014-09-23-15.45.35-1024x1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our old laptop, freshly awoken from 2007.&lt;/span&gt;
In a few weeks, my colleague Maribeth Gandy and I will be presenting a paper at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acm.org/uist/uist2014/&quot;&gt;UIST 2014&lt;/a&gt; (ACM’s User Interface Software and Technology conference), reflecting back on what we learned from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://ael.gatech.edu/dart/&quot;&gt;DART&lt;/a&gt; system (The Designer’s Augmented Reality Toolkit, the first paper on DART was published at UIST 2004!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;uist-files&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;uist-files&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2014/09/2014-09-23-15.46.03-300x300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some old files from 2005.&lt;/span&gt; 
Along with our paper, we want to demo some of the old work we did with DART, but 10 years is an eternity in computer time!  Fortunately, some of the old laptops and technology are still sitting on shelves, so today we fired a few of them up. Much to our surprise, one of the Toshiba laptops was actually hibernating, not shut down.  DART  was created as an extension to (then Macromedia, now Adobe) Director, the authoring environment for Shockwave content.  And, low and behold, Director was sitting there running!  Poking around, it appears we put this machine to sleep in 2007 or so;  it’s like waking a fairy tale creature (minus the kissing part).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;uist-fam-paint&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;uist-fam-paint&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2014/09/2014-09-23-15.45.52-300x300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Never finished editing that picture&lt;/span&gt;
If you look closely, you can see the cracks on the display (from us holding it up as a tablet;  this is one of those original convertible tablets from the early 2000’s, complete with Wacom Pen).  We’re very afraid to connect this to the internet;  it’s such an old unpatched version of Windows XP, god knows what will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other windows were open, too:  a file browser, where the newest date was the CVS directory (CVS, so old-school!), 2-18-2005, 5:24pm. And, a Microsoft Paint window, with a video frame from Four Angry Men open.  Good times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a lot of work to do resurrecting this stuff, but it’s going to be a ton of fun, and I’m really looking forward to bringing it all to UIST!   Here’s the lab table as I left it today, covered with a pile of tech more than a decade old.  See if you can find the tiny Intersense trackers that cost us ~$10,000 each back then!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Like Frankenstien&#39;s lab, where we are trying to review a demo from the dead.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2014/09/2014-09-23-17.12.25-1024x1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for old times sake, here’s a few videos related to DART.  First, the video from our UIST 2004 paper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/l7xdIcRYfBE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the video for Four Angry Men, probably the most elaborate AR experience we created back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/LmRd6XtVF0U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 17:43:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/23/preparing-for-uist-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/23/preparing-for-uist-2014/</guid>
        
        <category>DART</category>
        
        <category>Four Angry Men</category>
        
        
        <category>AEL</category>
        
        <category>demos</category>
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Claims the High Ground on Privacy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/16/you-are-not-an-iproduct/&quot;&gt;I blogged about an interview with Tim Cook&lt;/a&gt; where he made some great claims about Apple’s stance on privacy.  More keeps coming.  They are pushing everyone to two-factor authentication on iCloud, for example. Now, Apple posted a web page talking about how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/privacy/privacy-built-in/&quot;&gt;privacy is built into iOS and their services&lt;/a&gt;, which is chock full of wonderful things (and repleat with jabs at “their competitors”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On iMessage/Facetime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So unlike other companies’ messaging services, Apple doesn’t scan your communications, and we wouldn’t be able to comply with a wiretap order even if we wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On iCloud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unlike our competitors, we never scan any of your iCloud data for advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Maps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Other companies try to build a profile about you using a complete history of everywhere you’ve been, usually because they’re targeting you for advertisers. Since our business doesn’t depend on advertising, we have no interest in doing this — and we couldn’t even if we wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some companies mine your email for personal information to serve you targeted ads. We don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Spotlight Suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unlike our competitors, we don’t use a persistent personal identifier to tie your searches to you in order to build a profile based on your search history. We also place restrictions on our partners so they don’t create a long-term trail of identifiable searches by you or from your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk just this past Sunday on privacy and security in Internet of Things, Wearables and AR, and near the end suggested that a company with real products (Apple or Microsoft) could do exactly what Apple has done here:  take privacy seriously by &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; mining our data, and make that stance clear.  At a time when privacy concerns are going to keep growing and growing, as more and more problems come up with wearable and internet-enabled devices, the company who convinces people that their data is safe and secure with them has a lot to gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it looks like Apple just ate Microsoft’s lunch.  Again.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 05:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/18/apple-claims-the-high-ground-on-privacy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/18/apple-claims-the-high-ground-on-privacy/</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>microsoft</category>
        
        
        <category>commercial</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You are not an iProduct</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking lately about privacy and the relationship to the business strategies of various companies, and have become fond of saying that there are two companies:  ones that sell products and ones for whom you are the product.  Google and Facebook are the canonical examples of the later half (Google does sell some things, but largely does not, or does it at a massive loss).  Apple and Microsoft are canonical examples for the former.  There is a question, as The Googleplex continues to demonstrate the power of “free”, which direction Apple and Microsoft are going to go in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I firmly believe that both companies have an enormous opportunity to sell services and technology if they can convince people they are not making you their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just saw this quote from Tim Cook, that pretty clearly lays out where Apple stands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our view is that when we design a new service we try not to collect data. So we’re not reading your email. We’re not reading your iMessage. If the government laid a subpoena on us to get your iMessages, we can’t provide it. It’s encrypted and we don’t have a key.
Our business is based on selling [products]. Our business is not based on having information about you. You are not our product. &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macrumors.com/2014/09/15/tim-cook-on-privacy/&quot;&gt; courtesy of macrumors.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:57:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/16/you-are-not-an-iproduct/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/16/you-are-not-an-iproduct/</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        
        <category>commercial</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Need New Business Models in IoD</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Today, I gave a talk at the Ubiquitous Computing conference’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://appanalysis.org/upside/&quot;&gt;Workshop on Usable Privacy &amp;amp; Security for wearable and domestic ubIquitous DEvices (UPSIDE)&lt;/a&gt;, modestly titled “&lt;em&gt;Augmented Reality + Internet of Devices + Big Data: The End of Privacy?&lt;/em&gt;”
I’ll post something else about this talk soon, but one of the goals was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;to urge people to develop architectures for IoD&lt;label for=&quot;chang-ungar&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;chang-ungar&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;rutledge-massey-anton-swire-2014&quot;&gt;Rutledge, R. L., Massey, A. K., Antón, A. I., &amp;amp; Swire, P. (2014). &lt;i&gt;Defining the Internet of Devices: Privacy and Security Implications&lt;/i&gt;. Georgia Institute of Technology.&lt;/span&gt; This paper introduces the idea of &lt;em&gt;Internet of Devices&lt;/em&gt; (IoD), a term I like more than &lt;em&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; + AR that allow us to keep and control our data, sharing it or not as we see fit.  It may be that we choose to keep all our data local, or only share anonymous or agregated data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this goal, of course, is that some days it seems like the principle business model of tech companies right now is centered on the idea of giving things away and mining user data.  If we cut the cord to user data, what then of these services that folks have grown to love and expect to be free?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is an opportunity to create new business models that reflect this expectation of “free,” but that actually result in direct revenue.  Looking to the games industry, the “free to play” model has succeeded because they have figured out how to generate income from players at those moments when the players see value — if I have more coins/eggs/whatever, I could do “something” in the game.  Designers of F2P games have figured out how to walk the line of making games that are (at least somewhat) fun to play for free, but where spending real money adds enough value that people will happily fork it over.  And they do fork it over, in often disturbing amounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model won’t translate directly, of course. Many games leverage the same compulsions as casinos and other forms of gambling, withholding “fun” at just the moments it’s most tantalizing and then requiring players to spend “just a little bit” to keep playing.  It’s hard to imagine this model translating directly to a more mundane context, but the higher level point that people have demonstrated they will “paying a tiny amount at the moment when the user perceives real, tangible value” should translate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make this work, we’ll need a way to pay these small amounts.  In games, users buy “coins”, usually in bulk so they are easy to spend in the heat of the moment. (Those coins can typically also be “earned” in the game, giving users the illusion they could successfully play for free.)   Micro-transaction schemes haven’t worked well in the past, but if they can be smoothly integrated into an IoD context, there is enormous potential.  Given the appearance of systems to control these collections of devices (&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/homekit/&quot;&gt;HomeKit&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadgroup.org&quot;&gt;Thread&lt;/a&gt;, 
and &lt;a href=&quot;http://allseenalliance.org&quot;&gt;Allseen&lt;/a&gt;, 
to name a few), and the tie-in between these systems and existing payment infrastructures, the potential is certainly there.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 16:55:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/14/we-need-new-business-models-in-iod/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/09/14/we-need-new-business-models-in-iod/</guid>
        
        <category>business models</category>
        
        <category>free-to-play</category>
        
        <category>micro-payments</category>
        
        
        <category>commercial</category>
        
        <category>IoD</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HomeKit, Google, Facebook, Privacy and the Internet of Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While there is much that can be said about privacy, security, policy and the Internet of Things (in fact, I’m going to be co-teaching a graduate class at Georgia Tech on this very topic next spring), here I want to focus on one thing:  the invasion of your home and my hope Apple and their partners take privacy seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet connected devices that feed continuous information to cloud services are a big deal, in terms of privacy.  Right now, there are little isolated clouds that have access to bits of our information (think Fitbit or Jawbone Up, Loseit or Runkeeper, Cell-tower location, Amazon purchases, and so on).  But these are converging, and very soon will be able to be leveraged to infer unprecedented information about us, information we didn’t even imagine could be collected.  Apple’s HealthKit and Google Fit are going to start consolidating some of this, but most people still feel like that is something they would opt into (or not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devices we install in our home are different, because they are not linked to our phone, are not opt-in, and soon it won’t be possible to buy a fridge or thermostat that isn’t “smart”;  our water and electricity usage will soon be monitored as well for billing and to provide “better service.” Researchers at Georgia Tech and the University of Washington (Abowd and Patel, in particular) have already demonstrated this simple information can be used to create an accurate picture of usage of anything that uses water or electricity in the home.   And this, in turn, gives a surprising picture of life in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will make no secret of the fact that my initial reaction to Google buying Nest last year was to search for a decent alternative to our 3 Nest’s (haven’t found one yet, but the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lyric.honeywell.com&quot;&gt;Lyric&lt;/a&gt;  looks interesting).  When Facebook bought Moves, I deleted my Moves account and data.  While I use Facebook to keep in touch with relatives and some close friends, I generally do not link other services to it.  I make use of my share of Google services, of course. I use the web and am happy for Google to index the hell out of it;  I’m happy that a search for “Blair MacIntyre” on google.com yields pages and pages of links pointing at my pages, research, interviews, talks and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am not happy about giving Google access to this sort of always-on, always-collecting, deeply-personal information about my family and me.  I won’t use Android and I don’t use Chromecast, for similar reasons.  Some say “it’s no big deal, there’s no way to stop this information being collected, it’s not like anything bad can happen”, but I disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple put, I’m not willing to hand access to all aspects of my life to companies whose entire business model is based on building an increasingly accurate model of me, and monetizing it.  I’m not naive enough to think Apple is virtuous, but their business is not (yet) centered around monetizing a model of me (rather, it’s centered around locking me into their ecosystem and monetizing me in a much more direct way, though purchase of products and services).   It’s in Apple’s interest for me to trust them, for their ecosystem to be easy to use and tightly integrated, and that is actually reason for hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, as I see it, is that all of these connected devices are sending data directly to cloud services.  While convenient (I can turn on the AC at home via the Nest app, yay!), this is a massive data privacy and security problem:  specifically, the data is out of your control as soon as it leaves the house.  What needs to happen is for these Internet of Devices to be connected to personal clouds, preferably in the home, where homeowners have direct and understandable control over what leaves their house.  Right now, this can’t happen because each device is tied to a company who wants to retain control (of you, of the devices, of the services).  But, as the industry matures and consolidates, there is the opportunity for ecosystems to develop that companies need to make their devices work with, rather than going it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is why I am hopeful about HomeKit.  Apple is all about low-friction user experiences, and can easily create an environment where companies are incentivized to tie into it’s services instead of developing their own.  There is no reason these services cannot include home gateways (perhaps a future Airport base station, or even a future Apple TV?) that give users the opportunity to control, aggregate, filter or discard their data, as they see fit.  Apple can decide to provide users with guarantees that their data is not shared, that it lives in their iCloud account, and that it will not be looked at without their permission, because Apple doesn’t need that kind of information for their core business:  in fact, their core business can leverage that stance as a reason you should buy into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also, as you can imagine, why I am not at all excited about the corresponding Google or Facebook ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 06:43:41 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/06/20/homekit-and-the-internet-of-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blairmacintyre.me/2014/06/20/homekit-and-the-internet-of-things/</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>google</category>
        
        <category>homekit</category>
        
        <category>lyric</category>
        
        
        <category>musings</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
